Fatih Doğan

Istanbul, Istanbul, Turkey



fth.dgn@outlook.com



+90 545 728 49 36



linkedin.com/in/fatihdgn

Summary

This might come off as a bit cliché, but; I've been messing around with computers since I was a child. This curiosity became much more in time and expanded to electronic devices as a whole, but my main attraction was; these devices can "do stuff".

When I push a button with a letter on it, that letter actually shows on "something" that resemble a TV. When I click with something called a mouse to particular places; all of a sudden, certain things happen? These things always surprised me when I was a kid, and it still does sometimes since I get in to the software development business.

I was born in 94 at Bakırköy, Istanbul and raised in Istanbul too. I went to BilgeAdam's Software and Database Expertise program when I was a student at high school and received an outstanding achievement certificate at the end. I've graduated from Ahmet Yesevi University's Computer Programming associate program later down the line.

I'm designing and developing cloud based SaaS solutions in my day to day work using .NET and C#. Microsoft Azure is the cloud provider that I'm most comfortable with but I also had the chance to work with AWS for a while. For CI/CD stuff, I'm used to Azure DevOps, but I also know GitHub Actions enough to run my blog.

These are the tech stuff that I've been working with for a long time, and the things that I've worked for a while(*), ordered by my experience with them in chronological order.

- NET Framework
- Windows Forms
- ASP.NET WebForms*
- WPF
- ASP.NET MVC
- ASP.NET Web API
- VSTO Add-in (Outlook, Lync*)
- jQuery
- AngularJS
- Office Add-in (Outlook)
- Apache Cordova*
- Ionic Framework*
- UWP*
- Angular
- Vue*
- Electron*
- Microsoft Teams Store Application integration
- .NET Core
- Docker*
- Kubernetes*

- Flutter*

These are the programming languages that I've worked with, similar to the list above;

- C#
- JavaScript
- CSS*
- TypeScript
- PowerShell*
- C++*
- Pvthon*
- Lua*

Experience



Software Developer

VavaCars

Dec 2022 - May 2023 (6 months)

I've worked as a Front-end Developer, mainly on the front and center VavaCars website, and have been able to contribute to some features and changes, which they were varying from ordering process, vehicle detail, and representing legal documents.



Principal Software Developer

PEAKUP

Oct 2014 - Dec 2022 (8 years 3 months)

I've been developing all kinds of applications and SaaS services that mainly uses Microsoft Azure. Main one is a service called Authenticator that all of the services inside PEAKUP uses. It acts as a authentication layer and has Azure AD and Google Workspace account support.

I've used .NET Framework and .NET (Core) on most of the projects. For web projects, I used ASP.NET Web API or ASP.NET MVC for the backend and Angular for the frontend. For desktop applications, I've used WPF (MVVM) and Windows Forms for older projects.

Here are some other services that I've worked on. These are only the names because detailing all of them would exceed the character limit of this space;

- Approval
- Back & Drop
- Checkpoint
- ContactSync
- Domain Resolver
- EnviSense
- Exchange Rates
- Hodoor
- Licensing
- Meeting Manager
- One
- PeakDrive
- Quotes

- Sign & Go

System Administrator

Atiktuk

Feb 2014 - Aug 2014 (7 months)

I've worked here because I wanted to learn about infrastructure and integration between these systems. This experience helped me a lot throughout my career.

We had customers that has an SLA agreement with our company and I would physically go there and maintain their systems.

I would also manage the sites that we are hosting and help customers to fix issues.

(Aile) Software Developer

ASLI

Aug 2013 - Feb 2014 (7 months)

I've worked on couple of applications.

First one was an application for ordering from the table using a tablet. It was an application developed using Angular.js, jQuery and a ASP.NET MVC backend.

Second one was a frontend for the CRM application to ease some of the process using it. I've developed it using Windows Forms.

Education



Ahmet Yesevi Üniversitesi

Associate's degree, Computer Programming 2016 - 2020



2008 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

- **MTA: Software Development Fundamentals Certified 2016** Microsoft
- Exam 483: Programming in C# Microsoft
- Microsoft 365 Certified: Developer Associate Microsoft Issued Jun 2022 Expires Jun 2023
- Yazılım ve Veritabanı Uzmanlığı Katılım ve Üstün Başarı Sertifikası BilgeAdam Teknoloji

Skills

Angular • Angular Material • Block Element Modifier (BEM) • SASS • RxJS • Azure • Cloud Applications • .NET Framework • .NET Core • ASP.NET Core